<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Changes on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/tags/changes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Changes on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/tags/changes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Cloudant Support</title>
      <link>https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/2022/03/11/Getting-Cloudant-Support.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/2022/03/11/Getting-Cloudant-Support.html</guid>
      <description>Support is available for your paid IBM Cloudant Standard accounts but not for free, Lite accounts. This blog post shows how to raise a support ticket.
Photo by Matthew Waring on Unsplash
Note that you may still raise a support ticket against free IBM Cloud accounts pertaining to the subjects of account management, billing and IAM, just not support cases about specific Cloudant services.
Creating an IBM Cloud account If you haven&amp;rsquo;t done so already, create an IBM Cloud account at https://cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Changes Feed</title>
      <link>https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/2022/01/21/Using-the-Cloudant-changes-feed.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emlaver.github.io/gh-pages-example/2022/01/21/Using-the-Cloudant-changes-feed.html</guid>
      <description>A Cloudant database&amp;rsquo;s changes feed&amp;rsquo;s primary use-case is to power the replication of data from a source to a target database. The Cloudant replicator is built to handle the changes feed and performs the necessary checks to ensure data is copied accurately to its destination.
There is a raw changes feed API that can be used to consume a single database&amp;rsquo;s changes but it must be used with care.
The _changes API endpoint can be used in several ways and can output data in a variety of formats, but this article will focus on best practice and how to avoid some pitfalls when developing against the Changes API.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
