<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLI on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://emlaver.github.io/tags/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLI on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emlaver.github.io/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>couchreplicate</title>
      <link>https://emlaver.github.io/2018/02/22/Cloudant-Replication-with-couchreplicate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emlaver.github.io/2018/02/22/Cloudant-Replication-with-couchreplicate.html</guid>
      <description>One of Apache CouchDB™&amp;rsquo;s killer features is replication. JSON data is easily replicated between data centers, from a mobile device to the cloud, or vice versa. The CouchDB replication protocol is shared by Apache CouchDB itself, the IBM Cloudant database-as-a-service, Cloudant Sync libraries for iOS and Android and the PouchDB in-browser database.
Setting up a single replication is as easy as filling in a form in the Replication tab of your Cloudant or CouchDB dashboard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>couchdiff</title>
      <link>https://emlaver.github.io/2017/05/10/Diff-your-database-couchdiff.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emlaver.github.io/2017/05/10/Diff-your-database-couchdiff.html</guid>
      <description>The Unix diff command-line utility has been around since the 1970s. It compares two text files line by line and tells you the differences between them.
Photo by Hermes Rivera on Unsplash
If I diff two files a.txt and b.txt containing versions of the same poem I can find the differences between them with the command:
$ diff a.txt b.txt 2c2 &amp;lt; T.S. Eliot 1888-1965 --- &amp;gt; T.S. Eliot 6a7 &amp;gt; Sprouting despondently at area gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command-line tools</title>
      <link>https://emlaver.github.io/2015/10/19/Command-line-tools-for-Cloudant.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emlaver.github.io/2015/10/19/Command-line-tools-for-Cloudant.html</guid>
      <description>Some developers spend their days dragging and dropping in a graphical user interface, others are more comfortable typing green letters into a black background on a command-line terminal. If you are the latter type of developer, then this blog post is for you. We introduce a range of command-line tools that you can use to interface with IBM Cloudant (or plain Apache CouchDB).
Cloudant and CouchDB share an RESTful HTTP API allowing access from any programming language or from the command-line using the curl utility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
