<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on Cloudant blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.cloudant.com/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on Cloudant blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.cloudant.com/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysing Backups with SQL Query</title>
      <link>https://blog.cloudant.com/2019/04/23/Analysing-Cloudant-Backups-with-SQL-Query.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cloudant.com/2019/04/23/Analysing-Cloudant-Backups-with-SQL-Query.html</guid>
      <description>In this post we discussed storing time-series data in time-boxed Cloudant databases to allow recent data to be stored in Cloudant and older data to be archived and deleted from Cloudant. In this post we&amp;rsquo;ll examine how to query data that has been archived and backed up to Object Storage using the IBM SQL Query service.
Object storage is much cheaper per gigabyte than a database, is endlessly extensible and makes a great choice for storing backups and archived data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Data Warehouse</title>
      <link>https://blog.cloudant.com/2018/11/16/Cloudant-and-the-data-warehouse.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cloudant.com/2018/11/16/Cloudant-and-the-data-warehouse.html</guid>
      <description>Addendum: Since publication of this blog, couchwarehouse has added support for MySQL and PostgreSQL as well as SQLite. This post is still valid, but bear in mind you now have a choice of target database types.
One of Cloudant&amp;rsquo;s best use-cases is as a rock-solid, always-on operational datastore. It is built for fault-tolerance, storing multiple copies of your data on separate servers so that a Cloudant cluster can withstand the loss of multiple nodes without loss of service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying Cloudant with SQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.cloudant.com/2017/07/18/Querying-Cloudant-with-SQL.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.cloudant.com/2017/07/18/Querying-Cloudant-with-SQL.html</guid>
      <description>Cloudant and its Apache CouchDB stable-mate are &amp;ldquo;NoSQL&amp;rdquo; databases—that is, they are schemaless JSON document stores. Unlike a traditional relational database, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to define your schema before writing data to the database. Just post your JSON to the database and change your mind as often as you like!
One of the appealing things about relational databases is the query language. Structured Query Language or SQL was developed by IBM in the 1970s and was widely adopted across a host of databases ever since.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
